到了  时间刚刚好
Top ! In time !
感谢您选择乘坐  哈米德的拉风出租车
Thank you for choosing "Hamid taxis du bled".
希望您旅途愉快
I hope the trip was as good
你好  我也好
for YOU than for us.
但是我们很快就不能接着聊了
But I'm not telling you soon.
谁电话在响
Not my mp
抱歉
I'm sorry.
有电话来了  看看是谁
They call me. Who is it?
你好
Allo?
是叔叔吗
Allo uncle?
- 你谁呀  - 艾迪  你侄子呀
- Who's ? - Eddy, your nephew.
- 你想干什么  - 快开车来接我  不然我就死定了
- He wants what? - Give me the taxi otherwise I'm my '.
抱歉  你就去死去吧
Sorry, but you died then.
不  不  真的很重要  你还没意识到
No, it's very important. You do not realize.
- 我很惨吗  - 我进隧道了
- Too bad, - I go in a tunnel.
另外还有  信号不好  听不见
In addition, it is broken, the phone.
没信号啦
It is broken !
就是你在我车上画的鸡鸡  给我站住
Is it you who draw zizis on my car? Here!
要是你们还有人
So! If there is anyone yet
在我的出租车上画鸡鸡的话  我就得和他说道说道了
who draws a zizi on my taxi, he will deal with me.
听明白了吗
It's understood ?
我要抓5个你这样的人  我会把握机会的
5 people you are looking for. The odds I will take!
- 你什么都抓不到  我是无辜的  - 这话留着跟局长去说吧
- You'll take nothing: I'm innocent. - You'll tell that to the commissioner.
- 介意我抄个近道儿吗  - 走吧  我还赶着去打球呢
- Do you mind if you take a shortcut? - Go ahead, I fight my balls.
如果你同意的话
If you take it like that.
- 那你介不介意我再放个音乐  - 随你的便吧
- Do not you mind the music? - Let go of me.
走起
Go!
你可别跟我说
Do not tell me that
- 你还没系好安全带啊  - 我他喵的有手吗
- you have not put on your belt. - But I can not !
- 你想干什么  - 看好了
- What do you do to me? - Yes what ?
不  不  快停下
No, not stop!
你可坚持住了啊
Hang in there.
搞什么鸡毛呢
What are you doing ?
哦  我好像走错路了
Oh no, I was wrong!
停车
Stopped !
停车  好吗  就是我
Stop, OK, it's me!
我承认
It's me !
哦
Oh !
开慢点儿
Slow down there!
她咋刹不了车了
She does not advance!
看着点儿路
Look in front!
耶
Yeah!
哇哦
VVaouh!
好了  我全都交代了
OK, I tell you everything.
是希门尼斯
It's Jimenez.
- 继续说  - 你可看着点儿路吧
- Tell us. - Look in front of you !
- 我就知道这个  - 手不管用了
- I do not know more! - Without hands.
- 腿也不管用了  - 把手放好
- Knee! - Hands !
我可以告诉你他的地址  就在圣丹尼斯天堂大酒
Do you want his address? Paradis hotel in Saint-Denis.
312号房
Room 312!
你还好吧
It's okay?
别这么开了
Do not do that.
来了
Oh yes.
你看  只有一只手
Look, a hand!
交货时间是
The delivery
- 是这个周六六  - 周六几点呀
- is for Saturday! - At what time ?
下午三点
15h!
这不就对了嘛
That's it !
来拍照纪念一下吧
Greet the camera.
这狗东西
And shit.
猜猜谁登上了警界猛汉的封面
Guess who is still covering Keuf Mag.
车都给你开坏了
It's buggy!
如果不这么搞突击的话
If that, it does not accelerate my mutation
我怎么获取罪犯信息
to RAID, I do not understand.
先坐吧
Sit down.
马洛特  我把经费都花到了
Marot, I pass on the expenses
- 你的车的轮胎上  - 不就是爆了个胎吗
- tire of your vehicle... - It's just tires.
- 现在还有一个更严重的问题  - 我听着呢
- There is a bigger problem. - I listen.
你认识克里斯泰勒・布切洛特吗
Do you know Christelle Bucherot?
克里斯泰勒  这名字的人也太多了吧
Christelle... I knew a lot...
就昨天晚上和你在一起的那个人
The one with whom you spent the night yesterday.
克里斯泰勒  当然了
Christelle, of course!
- 她还好吗  我没跟她一起多久  - 是在农场
- She is fine ? I did not stay... - The farm.
当地长官叫什么名字
What is the name of the prefect?
长官叫
Mr. Prefect...
长官叫  叫
It's Mr. Prefect...
- 让・贝特朗  - 布切洛特
- Jean-Bertrand... - Bucherot.
对  就是布切洛特
Ah, here we are, Bucherot.
有意思  突然就想起来了  一个姓啊
It's funny, suddenly, it's the same name.
他们是一家人
There is a family link
还是  亲戚什么的
or of... maybe alliance?
他妻子
His wife.
- 她可没说起过  - 多亏
- she had not said it. - Thanks to
你的过往表现  你才不会被开除出队
your service records, you will not be written off.
但是你被禁止
But you are mutated
出外勤
on the field.
- 并不是我被升职到特警队吗  - 不是
- It is not the RAID I imagine? - Oh no.
- 不  - 你还是做警察
- No... - To the police
市政警察
Municipal.
到马赛去
From Marseille.
去南方吗
In the south ?
是的
Yes...
- 这不太适合我  离巴黎也太远了  - 马洛特  已经定了
- It does not suit me, it's far from Paris... - Marot, it's like that.
你可以走了
You can dispose.
你个没良心的
You have no heart.
去马赛吧
Marseille.
马赛
市政警察局
警界猛汉
收拾好了吗
Well-established ?
都好了
'It's okay.
我带你转转
I present to you.
- 能让你更快进入工作  - 是吗
- It will reassure you. - Ah yes ?
我们的队伍
Killer team !
生龙活虎
Dynamic.
我们一个一个来
Tenors. First,
那个坐着的家伙
you see the guy sitting,
留着怪怪的胡子的那个  他是梅纳德
the big bearded, weird, is Menard.
气场在地表之内  无人能敌
For the atmosphere, it's impeccable.
但他人超好  开放友好之类的
He is super nice, open, all that.
他无聊的时候就像个混蛋似的  而他是个很无聊的人
He's bullshit when he gets bored. And he's bored a lot.
一级警报  赶快出警
General alert! Intervention!
你们是刚从水烟酒吧出来吗
Did you go to a shisha bar?
你混蛋
Bastard!
那边的侏儒呢
And the dwarf,
- 是正式警察吗  - 听着  出于尊重
- it's regulatory? - Here, out of respect,
- 我们不会直接喊他侏儒  - 好吧
- we do not say "the dwarf". - Oh ok.
我们不以长短定好坏
We say nobody of small size.
这个侏儒是米歇尔  他  他的爱好
So the dwarf is Michel. Him, what he loves
就是微缩制品  制作模型  模具什么的
it's the miniature: model making, model...
他这个儿头
he has not a head
法国历史上很多著名足球运动员都叫米歇尔
- 怎么配得上叫米歇尔  - 他原先叫阿卜杜勒拉赫曼
- to be called Michel. - He was called Abdelrrahmane,
但是自从他皈依天主教之后  就叫米歇尔了
but since his conversion to Christianity, it's Michel.
- 是吗  - 没错  他找到了信仰
- Ah yes ? - Obliged. He found faith.
自那开始  我们在所有的宗教节日里大快朵颐的时候
Since then, we feast on all the religious holidays.
他却在圣诞的时候到处去传播福音
At Christmas, he wants cribs everywhere.
活得真累啊
It's hard.
而他一看到修女
And when he sees nuns,
- 情绪就异常兴奋  - 这合适吗
- he is very excited. - Is he radicalized?
谁说不是呢
Yes.
很是烦人  他对面的另一个
It's exhausting. And opposite, the other,
秃头顶的  是雷吉斯
with his head pervert, it's Regis.
我们总是笑他
We laugh more.
别盯着他看
Not in the eyes.
不行吗
Do not ?
- 可别看  - 好吧
- Please. - Ah?
雷吉斯钟爱间谍活动
Regis, he loves spying:
他经常监视他的妻子  但是他妻子还是离开了他
he was watching his wife, but she left him.
- 我明白了  - 请不要盯着他看  拜托了
- I understand it. - Do not look at him, please.
从那时起  他就变成了定位专家
Since then, he has become a geolocation pro.
好吧  我们局里有女孩儿吗
Well, are there girls in the brigade?
我正准备介绍给你呢  注点儿意啊
I was going to come there. Attention regal.
那边那个
There, right.
很辣眼睛的
It hurts the eyes.
- 桑德琳  警队里的队花  - 确定是队花吗
- Sandrine, the hottie of the brigade. - The hottie?
听好了
Attention,
13  14  15年连续三界被选为PACA区的
Elected Miss Police Municipal Region PACA
市政警花
警界之花
2013, 2014, 2015.
哦  很有份儿吧
Oh ! A piece.
- 是相当一大份儿  - 我们在一起巨开心的
- Yes, a piece. - It's heavy, we laugh more.
- 巨开心的  - 看这个
- Very heavy. - Look at this.
在车辆方面  我们都装备了些什么车
And at the level of the vehicles, are you equipped?
- 你喜欢车吗  - 喜欢
- Do you like cars? - Yes.
如你所愿
You'll be served.
你一定很饿吧
You were hungry.
14号车  没什么情况  我们去海滩吧
It unit 14. Nothing to report, we go to the beach.
你这车门是丢了吗
Do you miss a door?
是  门去修理了  还不知道能不能装回去呢
Yes, she is under revision: people do not do enough to overhaul!
你把我当傻子了吗
You take me for a con?
- 不  你怎么说都对  - 我现在已经非常紧张了
- No, that's right. - Already I'm upside down, there,
停车
stopped !
今天可不是时候  你看
It's not the day! You saw
比赛了吗
the game ?
我的小甜甜
没看
No.
- 你都不看比赛的吗  - 对  不看  我女朋友打来的
- Did not you see the match? - No. Yes, my girlfriend calls me.
抱歉
Sorry.
小甜甜
My sugar ?
你怎么样啊  我的小熊熊
How are you, my plump bear?
我和客户在一起呢
I am with a client.
我爸爸不在家  你要不要过来给我一个爱的抱抱呢
My dad is not here, you come to give me an express hug?
- 辣妹啊  - 好啊  但我现在不能
- Hottie. - Yes, but I can not,
我得去见雷内聊聊比赛的事情
I have to go see Rene to talk about the game.
你昨天就去聊了
You saw it yesterday.
- 是的  没有  是的  - 你去见你的朋友吧
- Yes... No... Yes.  - Va see your friends,
只有他们才能让你兴奋
they will cheer you up.
什么  说什么呢
What? What moral?
艾迪  我喜欢你  但是现在已经不可能了
Eddy, I adore you, but it's more possible.
- 我想要个真男人  - 什么
-  I want a man. - What?
- 一个能让我如痴如梦的人  - 谁能让你如痴如梦
- A guy who makes me dream. - Who makes you dream?
是谁带你去看的马赛对洛里昂的比赛啊
Who took you to see Marseille-Lorient?
- 那比赛烂透了  - 我们都没有
- Match in wood!  - We were not
挨着坐
sitting next.
毕竟票是赠的嘛
It was free!
我想要一个
I want
真男人
a man
- 一个有计划  有抱负的男人  - 我也有计划
- who has projects, ambition. - I have plans.
我的无麸质吉开酒项目正在进行中
My gluten-free chicha project is underway.
一切就要完成了
Everything is complete.
你没听懂  让我用你能理解的话来说
You do not understand. I try in your language:
我不需要一个替补队员
7th do not want a substitute.
我想要的是一个前锋  一个知道在我身前  身后活跃的前锋
I want an attacker who knows how to play in front, behind,
把我放在首要位置的前锋
that puts me goals in strength.
我说清楚了吗
It's clear ?
是的
Yes.
我父亲那边可是有
I have Brazilian origins
- 巴西血统的  - 胡说八道
- of my father. - The mytho!
我会把你点燃的
I'll fire you.
那我得叫消防员小哥哥来灭灭火了
Otherwise I call the fire department,
而不是去买
but not to buy
一本日历
a calendar.
喂
Hello?
你犯病了吧
You're ill !
没事的
It's okay,
- 我很厉害的  - 什么
- I master. - What?
你这车还想厉害个屁
You master nothing.
你他喵的是疯了吧
You're crazy mad!
我们会成为
We will do
最棒的队伍
a great team.
我们不用着急建立感情  我肯定会调回到特警队去的
It should not be attached too much, I must be transferred to RAID,
所以我不会在马赛呆太久的
so I will not stay in Marseille too much.
你做梦去吧
You think ?
占用公交车道
Bus Lane !
我去搞定它
I will do it!
我去吧
I arrive!
吃你的三明治吧
Finish the sandwich.
地方警察
Local police !
请停车
We stop.
他在做什么
What does he do ?
停下
Stop !
他会自己躲开的
He will push himself
这里  这个傻子
this con, there!
你这傻瓜  快停下
He stops this con, there.
你撞上了警察
Fada! You've built a conde.
但他是自己撞上来的
But it's not that his way to him!
宝贝
Honey !
我的小宝贝  你怎么样了
My little cat, how are you?
- 不  为什么是我  - 等下  我没事
- No ! Why me? - Wait, I'm fine!
我没事
It's okay!
我都说了是警察了  他们还不停车
Just say police, otherwise they do not stop.
我去搞定
I'll do it.
我要抓住他
I will do it!
你别来  你会拖我后腿的
You do not have to come, you're going to delay me.
- 系好安全带  - 我好兴奋
- Attach your belt ! - I'm excited!
你来吗
You come ?
我在这儿呆着  万一他回来了  还可以搜查
I stay here, in case he comes back, for the search.
走吧
Go!
终于有一次倒霉的不是我了
For once, it's not me.
- 他看起来非常生气啊  - 你真是吓到我了
- he looks angry and more. - You surprise me !
- 你就是个疯子  - 都2018年了
- You're a madman! - In 2018,
他们还会亲自站到车道上来让我们停车  这不正常啊
they put themselves on the path to stop us! It's normal ?
真是个白痴
What an idiot!
- 你说什么  - 我感觉不太舒服
- Sorry ? - I'm not fine.
让我专心点
Let me focus,
行吗
OK?
她还没有加速呢
She does not advance!
等下  帮我一下
Wait. Help me.
两个轮子也能开
It is on 2 wheels.
肯定是重量平衡了
Must be counterbalanced.
- 好吧  - 过去  过去
- Okay. - Go! Go!
我不想
I do not want!
- 像这样  - 不
- Like this. - No !
过去
Come on.
我们会翻车的
We'll turn around.
- 这辆车像个螃蟹一样  - 那是什么
- The car is in crab! - What is that ?
重量平衡了
Counterbalance.
一  二  三
One two Three.
- 好了  你给我在那儿呆好了  - 好的
- Come on, stay in your corner. - Yes.
好吧  他们追上来了
That's it, they arrive.
- 我感觉不太舒服  - 你什么意思
- I am not well. - What do you mean ?
我要吐了
I'm going to stack!
你别在我车里吐
You do not throw up here!
- 我要吐出来了  - 你想吐吗
- I am going to throw up. - Do you want to stack?
暴雨袭击哦
it rains behind.
不要啊
Oh no !
我不太舒服
'I'm not fine...
- 你还好吗  - 去你妈的
- It's okay ? - Abuse you.
- 好点了吗  - 你真是个混蛋
- It's better ? - Rigole, con that you are.
他是故意的
He did it on purpose.
我好想吐
I'm not fine.
不要
Oh no !
- 别吐在这儿  - 我心脏不好
- Not here. - I have heart.
我不太舒服
I'm not fine !
- 我要吐了  - 不
- I will stack! - No.
还跟着呢  我们来看看谁更熟悉马赛
Still there ? We'll see if you know Marseille well.
桑德琳
Sandrine!
看着点儿路啊
Look in front of you !
好好洗个澡吧
Good bath !
蛋糕都吐出来了
There are cakes!
嘿
Hey!
加油  使点劲儿
Come on, make an effort.
推我啊  西尔万
Push Sylvain!
推我的屁股
Push in the ass!
你们来的太晚了吧
Not too soon
欢迎来到马赛
Welcome to Marseille.
一个小小的市政警察发什么神经呢
The municipal police, fada or what?
你是哪个
Who are you?
以为自己很厉害吗
Empowered that you are.
- 他还不熟悉马赛而已  - 起开
- He does not know Marseille. - Leash.
我们知道你是谁  超级警察先生
We know who you are, Mr. super cop, parigot!
听着
Listen,
你现在在马赛  是龙也得给我盘着  是凤也得给我趴着
you are in Marseilles, you take care of your business and it will be fine.
明白了吗
Understand?
- 没事的  - 我要杀了他
- Its good. - I kill him !
- 我知道  冷静  - 我说了
- I know, calm. - I say it.
- 我们不会再麻烦你们的  - 不
- We won't bother you more. - No.
- 没事了  - 我的小宝贝怎么样了
- Its good ! - How's my little cat?
- 我告诉他了  - 没事了  对吧
- I told him. - It's good, what?
- 没事了吧  - 桑德琳
- It's okay ? - Sandrine!
好吧
OK.
会好的  让我来给你一个惊喜
It's good, I'll surprise you.
不是吧  我的包  天啊
Oh no, my bag! Oh, really!
有人吗  妈的
Someone there ? Oh fuck!
小甜甜
My sugar !
打过去
Go!
小甜甜
My sugar ?
- 我在大门口呢  惊喜不  - 我帮你开门
- I'm at the gate, surprise!  - I open you.
不  别开门
No, do not open.
喂
Hello?
还是开了  真是  美好的一天
Ah, here it is! Great... great day.
你想要如痴如梦吗
Do you want to dream?
是的
Yes.
那我就满足你
You'll be served.
我们要放贝多芬的音乐吗
Are we putting Beethoven?
神马
What?
这么重要的活动才不要放那种狗狗音乐呢
We're not going to put a music on dogs.
那糟透了  我来
It sucks. I manage
- 选音乐吧  - 好的
- the music. - OK.
我有一种被人
I have the impression
- 监视着的感觉  - 这是我爸爸
- to be watched. - This is my father.
他请了一个
He did it
- 很著名的画家画的  - 好吧
- by a great painter. - Okay.
那雕像呢
And the statue?
也是爸爸
Dad.
是我爸爸
It's dad.
很帅吧
Beautiful, huh?
是的  是的  好大个儿
Yes, yes... It is massive.
是的
Yes.
来吧
Come on.
怎么有火
Fire.
什么
What?
- 那儿  - 快去啊
- The ! - Move !
我又不是消防员
I'm not a firefighter.
- 快去灭掉  - 哦
- Turn it off. - Oh
那是香水
It's perfume!
把我爸爸的画拿走
Pick up my father's painting!
我知道
I know !
好烫
I am hot.
快把我解开
Come detach me right away!
危险
Warning !
吊灯要掉下来了  艾迪  把我解开
The chandelier will fall! Eddy, detach me!
您好
Hello.
这他妈的是在搞啥子
What fucking going on here?
不是你想的那样
That's not what you think.
你爸爸
Your father
的声音
has the same voice
和EA体育游戏里的一样
only in the game EA Sport.
其实你本人更帅的
You are better in real life.
更高雅
Elegant...
紧急集合
General alert!
好极了  怎么来的这么慢
Its good ! It's been so long.
这感觉真不错
That I feel good!
从退休之家
赶过来  花了我50分钟时间呢
我需要了解地形  嗯  比松
What I need is the terrain. Eh, Bichon?
- 是的  - 空地
- Yes. - Field.
请注意  这非常重要
Attention, the time is more than serious.
我们面临着更严峻的问题
We have a severe problem.
比奔驰大盗  比圣诞老人抢匪
It's more the niaks, it's more the Santa Claus,
比日本黑帮  比比利时人更严重的问题
it's more the chleus, it's even more the Belgians.
而且更糟糕
It's more serious.
什么问题
It is...?
黑人
Black people.
不是
No.
我知道
I know.
阿拉伯人
Arabs.
不是
No !
- 罗马人  - 不是
- Roma. - No !
上帝啊
My God...
意
Ri-ri...
熟肉酱
Rillettes.
完全偏离轨道
To the contravention.
- 不  - 是的
- No. - Yes.
不是闹着玩的啊
Do not play with me.
不要夸大其词
Do not exaggerate.
意大利人啊
Ritals!
- 不是说过了吗  - 啊  我
- It speaks to you? - AH I
确实  那是一伙强盗
Yes ! It's a gang of robbers
一个月内抢了五家珠宝店
who made five jewelry stores in one month.
- 今天早上他们又干了一票  - 比雄  这个设备
- They started again this morning. - Bichon, the device.
我们有
We have
五天时间  之后  马赛市将成为
5 days, and after, Marseille will be
世界关注的中心
in the center of the world,
我们这将会展示慕尚出品的
pearl the Mucem exhibition of diamonds
最新珠宝
i tutti Chianti!
这可不是闹着玩的
It is forbidden to ridicule oneself.
你们要四处巡查  找到所有的
You will start the spinning mills and find eyewitnesses
目击证人
who heard everything.
你认字吗
Have you read ?
还有就是
Something else,
我的民调支持率不太好
my polls are not brilliant,
嗯
huh?
我们不能让
The national police must not
国家警察领先我们一步  我们必须抢在前面
we walk in front of the feet. It's for the Mumu
为了马赛
fro Marseille.
我说明白了吗
I made myself understood?
明白  长官
HE CHEF!
这次的
I named
行动代号是  去他妈的
this operation "Vaffanculo".
长官  您会说意大利语吗
Sir? You speak Italian ?
不会  怎么了
No why?
- 您最好改一下这个代号  - 是的
- You must change your name. - Yes.
不  我喜欢这名字
No, I liked that...
去他妈的
Vaffanculo...
我再想想
I will find.
等一下
A second.
去他妈的  啊
Vaffanculo... Ah!
想到了
I found.
我给这次行动命名为
I named this operation, the operation...
黑手党
Mafia!
市长先生
The Mayor,
可是我们没有设备啊
we do not have the equipment.
嗯
Huh?
人手也不太够
We are too few.
查尔斯・马特尔在对战阿拉伯人的时候
And Charles Martel, in front of all the Arabs,
他也很孤独
he was alone!
我们还没那么糟
We can not do less.
我们有一个很棒的警察  那个超级警察在哪里
And we have a great cop. Where is the super cop?
- 我在这儿  市长先生  - 昆汀
- I am here, Mr. Mayor. - Quentin!
- 西尔万  - 米洛
- Sylvain. - Miro?
马洛特  但是
Marot, but...
请上来
Go up.
啊  是吗
Ah yes?
马林将会
Marin will be
带领着你们
your leader.
他将把他的专业知识
He will put his expertise to work
应用到马赛市  是吧  哈默
from Marseille, eh Hammer?
是的  但是我知道我只是这里的过客
Yes, but know that I'm only passing through here,
因为我还会回到特警队的
because I intend to integrate the RAID.
但如果你想离开这里
But if you want to get out of here,
就必须完成这个任务
it will have to torch this mission.
啊  是吗
Ah yes?
是的
Eh yes.
很好
Good,
调一下表
you set your watch.
- 现在几点了  - 14点12分
- What time ? - 14h12.
12点05分
12h05.
该吃午饭了
走吧
大家晚安
Good evening.
你看你还挺喜欢和我们在一起
You see that you like yourself
工作的
with us!
越快抓住这些意大利人  我就越早回家
The faster you catch the Italians, the sooner I get home.
好吧  我明白了  是的
Yeah, I understand. Ah yes...
你有什么发现
What do you find?
有一辆我们没发现的法拉利
A Ferrari by steering that we do not find.
加州法拉利  型号458
Ferrari California, 458...
这种车很难找的
With the Dacia, it's going to be hard!
哦
Oh?
是吗
You think ?
这两人是前四部的两位男主
可以肯定的是  如果是丹尼尔和艾米里  那就不一样了
It is certain that with Daniel and Emilien, it would have been different.
他们是谁
Who is that ?
- 丹尼尔和艾米里  - 我不认识
- Daniel and Emilien. - I do not know.
你不知道丹尼尔和艾米里吗
Do not you know Daniel and Emilien?
抱歉不认识
No, sorry.
即使在巴黎  他们也是众所周知的
Even in Paris, they are known.
呃  奔驰大盗啊
Uh... The Mercedes gang.
知道了吗
You mm?
90年代末
Robberies,
- 的抢劫案  - 是的
- late 90s? - Yes.
丹尼尔和艾米里逮捕了他们
Daniel and Emilien arrested them.
就在这
Here!
还有  如果你知道
Same for the... Ah! If you know...
那些日本人  也是
The Japaneses. The same.
还有
And
比利时的教父
the fathers, the Belgians,
丹尼尔和艾米里  艾米里  出色的警察
Daniel and Emilien! Emilien, big cop.
就是在这儿
It was there!
- 记忆有点衔接不上了  - 好吧
- I had trouble following. - Well then !
还有丹尼尔  丹尼尔开车特别牛
And Daniel. Daniel, what a pilot!
他的出租车与众不同
what he wanted from his taxi.
改装的像个火箭赛车一样
It was a rocket, a racing car.
我们甚至都看不见他  像阵风一样
We did not even see him go by. There was a plaque coming out
他的手套箱里
from [lia to m
有很多按钮
with buttons.
然后
And there,
出租车能从地面升起
the taxi rose from the ground.
他的车还能自己变形
He was transforming himself.
然后车牌自己就换了
New plate for the... Good.
马力全开
Go Om !
他就开着那部出租车在这里
The taxi that it was! When he left, he tore
四处遨游
总之
Including.
你不明白
You did not understand.
他毁了所有的测速雷达  当他经过的时候
He burned all the radars. They were falling
它们都失灵了
when he passed.
有次他去巴黎
你猜他怎么去的
乘飞机去的
By the airs.
他们被一架军用飞机空投了下去
They were parachuted by a military plane
飞行员正是丹尼尔的岳父
of Daniel's father-in-law.
飘在空中
And in the air,
出租车滑翔着
the taxi was floating.
我发誓大家都这么说的
I swear ! I was told.
他的车还能伸出
He released
- 飞行翼  - 飞行翼
- wings. - Wings ?
- 飞行翼  - 不可能
- Wings. - No.
我向你发誓
I swear to you
以吉伯特的名义
on Gfi?
听着
Listen!
对不起
Sorry.
那辆出租车在哪儿
Where is this taxi?
艾米里已经不是警察了  丹尼尔住在迈阿密
As Emilien is no longer in the police and Daniel lives in Miami,
所以我也不知道
I dunno.
也许可以问问丹尼尔的侄子
Maybe by asking Daniel's grand-nephew.
肯定是老婆家的侄子
It must be his nephew by marriage,
有点奇怪的孩子
he is a little weird.
不过  现在我只对那个出租车感兴趣
At the same time, there is only the taxi that interests me.
是啊  我们得找到出租车
Well yeah. We must find this taxi.
有了这个出租车  我一定能抓住那些意大利人佬
And with this taxi, I'm catching the Italians.
意大利佬  苏格兰佬  都能抓到
Italians, Scots, everyone.
- 真的吗  - 是的
- That is true ? - Yes.
我觉得丹尼尔和艾米里都已经过时了
I think Daniel and Emilien, it is outdated.
就像是星际迷航之类的  巴尔和比尔  奥利弗和汤姆
It's like Starsky and Hutch, Ball and Bill, Olive and Tom,
都过时了
It's over.
因为现在才是最主要的
Because now it's treasure
- 我们有马洛特  - 听起来不错
- and Marot! - It sounds good.
我不会丢下
I would not have left
每个人的
alone.
你已经不是孤军作战了  我会帮你的
You're not alone anymore. I'm here for you.
- 你也会帮我  对吧  - 谢谢你在我身边说这些
- You're here for me, huh? - Thank you for being there for me.
别客气
You're welcome.
- 要是没有你肯定会很难的  - 那肯定的
- It would have been hard without you. - It's clear.
现在  我们是二人组了
And now, we are two.
没错  - 二人合心  其利断金
- Yes. - We are stronger.
没什么能击败我们的
Nothing will happen to us.
没错
Nothing at all.
- 我们会怎么样  - 战无不胜
- What will happen to us? - Nothing !
不  没事的  明天我就能下地走路了
No, but it's nothing, tomorrow I'm up.
我们会去调查
We will investigate.
- 好的  - 艾兰和西尔万
- Yes. - Alain and Sylvain,
情同手足
the 2 fingers of the hand.
对  没错
Take it, yes.
放松点
Rest.
好疼啊
It hurts.
没事吧
'It's okay ?
我们知道是谁撞了你
We know who overthrew you.
我们查明了丹尼尔甥孙的身份
We have the identity of Daniel's grand-nephew.
好吧
OK, you have
- 叫什么  - 艾迪・马克罗夫
- his name ? - EDDY MAKLOUF.
两个人同名
A namesake.
- 没错  - 住在一个地址吗
- Yeah. - Do they live at the same address?
那真的是太巧了
That would be pretty amazing.
你们俩傻不傻
You are stupid,
- 这就是一个人  - 我真喜欢你发脾气的样
- it's the same person! - I like when you talk badly.
走吧
Go away.
没事的
It's okay.
1  2  3
ONE TWO THREE !
停下吧
Stop, really.
这门披了铠甲肯定
She is armored.
- 不  是木头的  - 老大
- No, it's wood... - Chief,
我去吧
I go !
不
No !
桑桑德琳
Sandfine!
他妈妈的
His mother.
- 警察  - 你们傻吗
- Police. - You are stupid,
撞门干嘛  这门是开着的
you could hit, it was open.
好烫
It burns.
刺疼啊
It stings !
老哥  为什么
Sir, why
那么做
did that?
他来的那么凶
He was aggressive.
啊  我好痛
Ouch! It burns me!
刺痛
It stings !
长官  抱歉
Sir, sorry.
拒绝配合调查  超速行使
Refusal to comply, speeding,
我会把你交给重案组的
I pass you the intentional homicide on agent.
我很难受
'I'm not fine.
我也是
Neither do I.
我快崩溃了
I'm close to burnout.
实际上  我女友还甩了我
In addition, my girl threw me.
那正好  那你就能在监狱里好好休息休息了
That's good, you're going to rest at Les Baumettes.
是的
Yes.
做个交易吧
I have a deal.
你给我找到这个出租车  我就既往不咎
You find me the taxi and I forget everything.
- 还不错吧  - 是的  但是我做不到啊
- It's not bad, is it ? - Yes... But I can not.
这个出租车
The taxi,
被我们送回去了
we sent it to... at the bled.
- 送回去了  - 我欠了20万的债
- Back home ? - He had 200000 on the counter,
就把车还给我叔叔了
we sent him to my uncle.
我可以跟你
I can offer you
- 做笔交易妈  - 说说看吧
我们可以组个队啊
If I find you, we could team up.
就像在绝地战警里一样  你是威尔・史密斯  我是马丁・劳伦斯
As in Bad Boy, you'll be Will Smith and I, Martin Lawrence.
- 我们不能组队  - 不能吗
- We will not team together, no. - No ?
- 不能  - 可惜
- No. - Pity.
本来可以找到那些意大利人的
I could have found these Italians.
什么
What?
我认识这里所有人  本来能帮你的
I know everyone here, I could have helped you.
本来还可以找我开优步的朋友帮忙
I could have asked my friends Uber.
但是看起来不太可能了
But apparently, it's not possible.
无意冒犯
Without disrespecting,
你现在团队也太弱鸡了吧
your team there is a little Cotorep?
并不是  没有啊
So that, not at all.
没有吗
Not at all?
他们很有活力
They are dynamic.
好吧
Okay.
什么都逃不过他们双眼
And nothing escapes them.
- 他们  - 是啊
- They are... - Ah yes.
你好  长官
Hello chef.
- 梅纳德  - 多亏了桑德琳的
- Menard. - Thanks to the photo
照片
of Sandrine,
我才能画出机器画像
I was able to draw a robot portrait.
艾迪・马克罗夫
Eddy Maklouf.
马赛市最垃圾的
The worst driver Uber
优步司机
from Marseille.
没错
Exactly...
你好
Hello.
他逃不过双眼睛的
It will not escape me.
我们出发
Lets' go !
我没事  我们走  去抓住他
I'm not bad, we go! We'll catch him.
带好手枪和双节棍
Take the guns and nunchakus.
跟我一起来
Join me !
那是什么
What is that ?
绿色之城马赛
部长女士  音乐停
Mrs. Minister! Cut.
我迟到了
I am late.
现在照相吧
Now, photo!
我们在笑什么  我还准备了个演讲呢
What are we laughing! I have a speech to make.
如你们所知
As you know,
我们主要的担忧
our main concern,
就是生态环境
it's ecology!
我将荣幸地为大家带来除狗粑粑
So I have the pride to present you the absolute weapon
不可或缺的武器
against the dog excrement.
KK
奏乐啊
Play,
傻逼们
stupid!
没错
Yes !
这里不再是狗的厕所
This is no longer the karcher
我们将全面的清理马赛
we will clean the Marseillaise... Marseille.
纯电动车
用KK2000清理车
It's with the KK 2000.
这辆车每日每夜
This vehicle is able to suck
能吸走35000颗
35 000 dog poop per day
狗粑粑
and by night!
所有
All,
都收集起来
is collected
碾碎  压缩
crushed, compacted,
最后
Finally...
放在这宝贝里
in this wonder.
抱歉  我们该怎么倒掉
Excuse me, for the emptying,
是的
you do
- 怎么倒掉  - 很简单
- how? - It's simple,
只要这么一按
we support and pif.
来了
Yes!
快给他们
A Kleenex
拿点儿心相印
for the sinister!
别动  因为
Do not move because...
这个会漏下去
It oozes.
亲爱的  是我
My sugar, it's me.
你没来电话  我已经联系你好多次了
You do not call me. I have called you many times.
我可是你的小熊熊啊  你怎么能把我忘记
It's your plump cub, do not hesitate to remember me.
我狠担心  担心你
I'm worried about... I'm worried, what.
电话响了  可能是你的
It sounds, maybe it's you.
哈米德  怎么了
What Hamid?
- 对  我们查到车了  - 号码
- Yes, we get the car. - The number.
- 装箱号是哪个  - 668
What is the container number? 668.
我要大笑的奶牛
And I want the Laughing Cow.
就是这个
It's this one.
我怎么才能把大笑奶牛交给你呀
But how can I add you to the Laughing Cow?
还有蜂巢
And Honey Pops.
好吧  我把蜂巢给你邮过去  真蜂巢
Yes, I sent you the Honey Pops, the real ones!
我还没收到
I have not received.
你待着吧  我们去工作了
Well, I leave you, we work.
好吧  你想要维塔尔卡  我会送给你的  拜拜
OK, you want a Vitale card, I send it to you, ciao.
真的是醉了
He drank me.
1  2  3
ONE TWO THREE.
传说中的出租车
The famous taxi.
- 这都是真的吗  - 是
- Was all that true? - Yes.
你以为这就是传奇了吗  其实我叔叔才是传奇
You take me too much for a mytho. My uncle, it's a legend.
它
'It,
这是什么踏板  那是刹车
what's the pedal of what? That's the brake...
- 先动动雨刷吧  - 好的
- Put a wiper's blow already. - Yes.
- 那是转向灯  - 我知道
- It's the turn signals. - I know.
来了
Here.
你真的会开车吗
Are you sure you can drive it?
怎么了
What?
你知道我是谁吗
You know who I am ?
我是艾迪・马克罗夫  丹尼尔的侄子  一个存世的传奇
I am Eddy Maklouf, the nephew of Daniel, a living legend.
天生就有开车的血脉  所以没错  我能开得飞起来
Piloting is in the genes. So yes, I can fly it.
- 那我们走  - 不  我来说  懂吗
- Let's go. - No, let's go, OK?
你  我会装作你刚才什么都没说
You... I'll pretend I did not hear anything.
好  我们走吧
OK here we go.
我超爱这个声音  马上来更猛的
I love this sound. Hang on, it'll go strong.
你熄火了
You stalled.
不不  我没有
No !
你确实熄火了
Oh yes !
是由于推动我们产生了前进的离心力
It's the centrifugal force that propels us forward.
你这祖传的基因是隔辈传吧
Genes have skipped a generation?
你给我压力太大了  我很难集中注意力
You stress me, I concentrate badly.
你有驾照吗
Do you have the permit?
什么
What?
你的驾驶证
Your permit.
有啊  我是C2的本呢
Yes, I have my automatic license.
- 你的什么证  - 什么
- What's your permit? - What?
我有自动挡的驾驶证
I have my automatic license.
- 当然了  - 对
- Oh yes. - Here.
这是手动挡的  我不知道该怎么操作
It's a manual, I do not know how to drive it.
- 左边的踏板是干什么用的  - 那是离合
- The pedal on the left is used for what? - It's a clutch.
- 对  - 你不知道怎么开车
- Yes. - You do not know how to drive.
对
Yes.
不
No.
- 市长先生  - 我是吉伯特
- Mr. the mayor? - It's Gibert.
烤馅饼从烤箱里出来了
The calzone comes out of the oven.
我重复以便  我们观察到
I repeat, we note.
烤馅饼从烤箱里出来了
The calzone comes out of the oven.
不好意思  我没听懂
I'm sorry, but it's not clear.
意大利人开始进攻了
The ritals are attacking.
拉响警报  天堂街518号
General alert. 518 rue de Paradis,
现在听清了吗
it's clear there?
托尼奥  快来吧
Avanti Tonio!
- 听着  感觉像是陷阱  - 有吉伯特在场
- There, it smells the trap. * - With Giben 'on the spot,
那会是个陷阱吗
does it smell like a trap?
快
Run!
他说什么
What?
换下位置
Move.
我跟这辆车还不熟
I do not know her.
让我再跑个两三圈  我一定会轻松上手的
Let me do 2 or 3 rounds, I can get used.
我又不是你教练
I am not a monitor.
再过两三个坎就行
Just 2 or 3 slaloms.
有音乐可以放吗
Do you have music?
这里有一张旧CD
Yes, there is an old CD.
我们出发吧
Let's go !
全员出警
General alert!
我的天
Oh Ohlala!
傻瓜
The morons
都是些傻瓜
The morons!
为啥要一起出来
All at the same time.
他们得有多蠢
How stupid they are!
我们这是在浪费时间  那两个
We are wasting time. The two remaining,
你  还有你
you and you,
快点
quick !
- 你不想休息一下吗  - 不想
- You do not want to rest? - No.
海边的空气会对你有好处的
The air of the sea will do you good.
巴黎的空气才对我有好处
The air of Paris will do me good.
你说得对
You are right.
你准备好了
Oh, you're fine!
去机场
The airport,
- 快  - 好的
- and quick. - Yes.
奇基塔  千北  千北  奇基塔
Tchiki Chikita, Chikita Tchiki
奇基塔有着迷人的外表
Tchikita She has the look that kills, Tchikita
像尼基塔一样的长发
Long hair like Nikita
如果她不离开我
If she does not leave me
我也不离开她  奇基塔有着迷人的外表
I do not leave her, Tchikita She has the look that kills
千北  像尼基塔一样的长发
Chikita, long hair like Nikita
抱歉
Sorry...
别打扰我  你没看见我正陶醉吗
Leave me alone ! You do not see that you disturb?
我正在状态为什么你不让我唱完这首歌
I was inside Why do not you let me finish it?
我受够了
I am wary :
在完整的灵感里面
these reactions
- 这些反应  是很打击人的  - 抱歉
- in full inspiration, it hurts. - Sorry.
- 很悲伤  - 我没这么想
- It's sad. - I did not think.
那你就别想
So, do not think,
不然就是场灾难
it would be a disaster.
- 乖乖听就行了  别作声  - 好的
- You listen, no comment. - Okay.
即使那样也太过分了  我们在执行任务
Even that is too much! We are still on a mission.
我再也不想听见什么杂音
I do not want to hear anymore
乱飞的苍蝇或者抱对儿的蜻蜓  我都不想听见
the flying fly and the dragonfly kissing him. Nothing
集中注意力
Let's stay focused.
去吧  你盯着他
Go ahead, you point him,
把锤子带回来  你不相信我吗
you bring back the Hummer. Do not you trust?
你太害怕了
You are scared.
我给你带来麻烦了吗
I already put you in trouble?
- 只有一次  - 我要离开整整2个月
- Only once? - I'm going out of 2 months firm.
- 你去出个唱片都够了  - 对
- You came out with pecs and an album. - Yeah.
除此之外呢
'Apart from that?
除此之外  那个别墅里  有12只斗犬
Other than that, the villa, there were 12 pitbulls,
它们把我咬伤了
they snatched me a piece of tail.
那没事  会好的
It's okay, it pushes.
你相信我吗
Do you trust?
不
No.
- 你不相信我吗  - 不
- Do not you trust? - No.
不相信吗
Do you trust?
对
Yes.
去给我搞定那个四驱车然后把它带回来
Go point me this 4X4 and bring it back.
上吧  伙计
Go ahead, man.
不是现在  兄弟  不是
Not now brother, not...
一切已就位
Everything in his camp,
猎物出窝了
the sheep will be well parked.
快给我滚出来  老女人  快滚出来
Go the little old woman, go out quickly!
我会射爆你的轮胎
I pete you the tire,
- 我会用烟雾呛死你  - 他是你的朋友吗
- I'm going to smoke you. - Is he a friend of yours?
不  这应该是劫车的
No, it would be more of a car-jacking.
好  我要给他点颜色看看
Yes! I'm going to make him dirty.
他再也不会感到膨胀了
He will not inflate them anyway.
抢劫了抢劫了
It's a fucking robbery!
举起双手
Hands up!
把珠宝放进去
Put the jewels.
别动  混蛋
Do not move, asshole!
- 没事吧  - 没事
- It's okay ? - Yes Yes.
- 有个问题  - 什么
- A question. - What?
你是哪个小队来的  这里的警察
What unit are you from? The keufs are not driving
可不会这样开车
like that.
不是
It's not
这条路
the road !
我只会
I do not do
紧跟警方的车队
than follow the police.
这边就绪了
Its good.
打给他
Tell him.
怎么
Hello?
我们到了
We arrive.
我们准备好了
We are ready.
一旦他们带着赃物品出去  我就卡住他们
As soon as they go out with the booty, I stuck them
然后就这样  大功告成
and there it is, finished!
就胜利了
La Traviata.
快  把钱给我
Hurry, give me the money.
有动静了
It's wriggling.
黑手党
Mafia!
在这儿呢
Well, here it is!
我还不知道法国的出租车
能跑这么快
看着都疼
It hurts !
- 想玩玩嘛  - 那就来吧
如果你再开快点
I am dead
我就要死了
if you break it.
那里都撞坏多少辆车了
How many are there?
这条路限速50公里
It's limited to 50.
别慌
Stay calm,
没事的
it will be fine.
我很冷静
I'm calm.
冷静
Calm !
不是吧  这些车都是从哪里来的
Yes! Where do all these cars come from?
走快车道
On the fast axes,
我们还占下风
we are beaten.
那就左转
Then take a left.
- 什么时候  - 现在
- When? - The !
我们赢了
右转
To the right.
这样我们会
We'll kill
伤到行人的
somebody.
别担心
Do not worry,
都在我的掌控之中
I manage.
- 别碰我  - 抱歉
- Leave me alone ! - Sorry.
艾迪
Eddy?
我来处理
I handle that.
艾迪要来了  大家快回家
Eddy is coming, come home!
这是马赛最古老的街区
This is the oldest district of Marseille.
看来他并不在意
Well, he does not care.
我的天
My God.
这场面怎么收拾
What ugliness.
艾迪
Eddy
在旧港口边有一辆黄色的法拉利
a yellow Ferrari on the Old Port,
- 你有兴趣吗  - 谢谢你
- Are you interested ? - Thank you.
那辆车
It is
- 在旧港口  - 怎么走
- on the Old Port. - Or ?
从那里  通过几条小路
There, by the small roads.
我们快没时间了
We do not have time anymore.
你在做什么
What are you doing ?
抄近道
It's a shortcut.
从那里吗
Over there ?
抓稳了
Hang in there.
好耶
'Ole!
- 这可不好  - 还没完呢
- It's not good. - It's not over.
又追上了
哦  停下
Oh, stop!
要撞车了
We will type.
拜拜
Ciao, ciao!
哦  没事儿了
Oh no, that's okay.
本来跟着他们的
We kept them.
我们要炸锅了
We're going to be badgers.
你总是小题大做  明天大家就把这事忘了
You dramatize everything. Tomorrow, everyone will have forgotten.
明天忘不掉的意外
好吧  好吧
Yes, yes.
- 嗯  我在上面  - 嗯
- Yes, I was there. - Yes.
每次都会有点事
Every time, there is something.
部长在普拉多出事故了
The minister, an accident on the Prado,
连环车祸  他们在警察内部
a pileup. They have a mole
有内奸吗
in the national police?
我们怎么办
What do we do ?
重新整理出租车  决不能再受这种屈辱
Reboost the taxi. Never again such humiliation.
我知道全马赛最好的修车店
I know the best garage in all of Marseille.
是吗
Ah yes?
要有信心
Have confidence.
走吧
Let's go.
米歇尔  快热身  你要上场了
Michel, warm up, you will enter the field.
这里吗
It's here ?
- 真的  - 这是家里的店
- Serious? - It's the family.
你妹妹吗
Your sister ?
对的
Yeah.
- 你是被领养的吗  - 不是  怎么了
- Have you been adopted or what? - No, why?
像这样
Like this.
你好
Hello.
你要是开出去  叔叔会干死你的
If it's you who drove it, uncle will fuck you.
- 她认识这辆车  - 她是有点为所欲为
- She thinks about the car! - She does what she wants.
嘿  还是先看看吧
Hey, but... Go ahead...
你可以
You could
帮我把车重新修理一下吗
the rebooster and me, I could
回头也许能请你喝一杯
invite you to take a pot.
也许在巴黎是这样  但你现在是在马赛
Maybe it works in Paris, but here you are in Marseille.
在这里要请人喝酒
Will have to be more original to go
光这样可不够
have a drink.
我会看看的  明天就会好很多
I'll take care of it, it'll be better tomorrow.
还有
And...
- 那个  你喜欢海豚吗  - 嗯
- Otherwise, do you like dolphins? - Yeah.
我也是
Me too...
这些都是球员
It's the players who play.
他们都是按照教练说的
They play as their request to play
踢的
the coach !
要是我的员工不听我的
If my employee does not do what I want,
我早疯了
I'm crazy outside.
她不接我电话  我不知道该发什么表情
She answers me more. I do not know what smiley to send him.
微笑行吗
Either smiley
这都没关系  你知不知道
"It does not matter", you know?
还是发个这样的坏笑
The one who is like that. Or the raging smiley.
那个歪嘴巴的
The one with the mouth.
你甩了我
"You left me".
我还犹豫  真可惜没有什么表情
I hesitate. Too bad there is not a smiley
能像阿尔及利亚人那样
Algerian, something like that.
你要有个妹子
And you would have the same
也会这样的  你觉得呢
for girls in blow drying. What do you think?
你问我吗
You ask me ?
对
Yes.
你已经说了两个小时了
It's been 2 hours that you talk about your gadgi.
我都要疯了  雷内
I'm going crazy. Rene!
- 怎么了  - 给我点冰块
- Yeah? - Give me some ice cubes.
给我2分钟  马上就来
2 minutes, I arrive.
西尔万  这是小巴
Sylvain, here is Baba,
我最好的朋友
my best friend.
- 终于  - 你是认真的吗
- Finally, I thought. - Are you serious ?
嗯
Yes.
我就把接力棒交给你了  我听不下去了  祝你好运
I give you the relay, I can not anymore. Good luck.
妈妈咪呀
On my mother.
嗨  小巴  谢谢
Hi Baba, thanks.
- 谢谢  兄弟  - 你把你朋友都累坏了
- Thank you, brother. - You're exhausting all your friends.
这里是优步司机酒吧吗
This is the Uber HQ?
怎么了
What?
我的女友  前女友
It's my girl. My ex-girl.
我要见她
I had to see her,
但她不肯见我
but she has an evening.
她太美了  我配不上
She is too beautiful for me.
换做平时  我喜欢的女孩肯定高兴的要疯
Usually, the girls I'm interested in are nuts.
- 看着像是你妹妹经常来  - 就那一次
- Seen like that. Your sister comes often... - And there, for once
一个漂亮的  聪明的女孩  对我感兴趣  我该怎么办
that a pretty, intelligent girl is interested in me, what do I do?
- 我在家打游戏  - 那太傻了
- I'm at home talking about games. - That's stupid.
- 你妹妹  - 那很傻吗
- Your sister... - That's stupid?
- 你就这么给我鼓劲吗  - 这是种表达方式
- Do you have that to cheer me up? - It's an expression.
你妹妹会来吗
Your sister is coming...
那些意大利人呢
And for the Italians?
他们肯定渗透进政府了
Must infiltrate the environment.
你有线索吗
Do you have tracks?
我唯一认识的意大利人是拉希德
The only Italian I know is Rachid.
他是同父还是同母来着
But he's from father and mother...
- 他是意大利人吗  - 他父母可能在这
- He is from Italy? - It is of parents in galley,
但他不是意大利人
but he is not Italian, he is...
- 好吧  - 但这是意大利人
- Okay. - But here is an Italian.
他是这里的
There he is from here.
- 我不知道你有没有  - 好吧
- I do not know if you... - Yes it's...
- 拉希德不是意大利人  - 不是
- Rachid, it's not Italian. - No.
他在意大利有朋友
He has a jersey from Italy,
皮耶罗的  但是
from Del Piero, but...
意大利  1  2  3
意大利万岁  123
拉希德
Rachid!
- 小姐  - 拉希德
- Senorita. - Rachid.
很虐
It's a bomb.
我跟你说了多少次别叫我拉希德
"How many times have I told you not to call me Rachid?
你在桌上看到什么  蒸粗麦粉  还是塔吉锅
What do you see on the tables? Couscous, tajine?
不  是披萨
No, it's pizza!
我叫里卡多  妈的
My name is Ricardo, shit!
- 这是谁  - 啊
- Who is it? - Huh?
- 这是谁  - 拉  里卡多  我朋友西尔万
- Who is it? - Ra... Ricardo, my friend Sylvain
是警察
of the police.
她真的到法定年龄了  不关我的事
For everyone she was major, it's not just me.
- 当然当然  - 她都40了
- No no not at all. - She's 40 years old.
不是这样的  嘘
Not at all, hush.
- 不  不 - 好吧  我明白  我明白
- No no. - OK, I understood, I understood.
我明白了
I understood.
- 我知道你们为什么来这了  - 不是
- I know why you are here. - No.
我知道了  我知道
Yes, I know, I know.
好吧
OK...
跟我来
Come with me.
不是
No !
不是这样的
It's not at all that.
下注吧  要开了
Place your bets. Burst the bank.
有意思
Interesting.
我们不是为这来的
We did not come for that.
14  不是吧
14. Unbelievable.
- 为什么  - 不是为那个
- Why ? - Not for that.
妈的
Oh fuck...
这儿呢
Here.
不用说
Useless to say
这是我的收藏
What is my collection?
疯了  这里他喵的是战后伊拉克吧
Crazy stuff, it's lrak here.
告诉我你对意大利人了解多少
Tell me what you know about the Italians.
你说什么意大利人
What Italians are you talking about?
艾迪  把那放下
Eddy, put that down, mess!
抱歉
OK sorry.
窃贼
Stealers,
- 你见过他们吗  - 乱说话会遭报应的
- did you see them? - It'll fall back on me,
所以我谁都没见过
so I saw nobody.
我能开几枪吗
Can I shoot with?
不行  别碰
Do not touch !
- 那我不动了  - 好
- It's not true ! - OK !
好吧
Okay.
如果我邀请警察过来呢
What if I invited the cops here?
- 你见过他们吗  - 他们来吃过
- Have you seen them? - They came to eat.
意面
Pasta.
不  没有意大利人会来
No, no Italian comes to eat
你的餐馆吃饭  你卖了武器给他们  有还是没有
in your restaurant. You sold them weapons? Yes or no ?
有  不  一点点
Yes. No. A little.
哪一种的
Which ones?
小型的武器  非进攻性的武器
Small... Steps... Inoffensive weapons...
真的非常非常无害
Really very very harmless.
不  看这里  看这里
Oh no, here, there, there.
- 出什么事了  - 后面有什么
- What is happening ? - What's behind?
- 哪啊  - 墙后面
- Where ? - Behind the wall.
哇呜
Wow!
你看到了吗  这是邻居  就在我家后面  我都没见过
Did you see that ? The neighbor, behind my house, I had not seen.
这是我餐馆用的
It's for my restaurant.
- 好吧  - 没错
- Okay. - Yes !
我们需要草药  就像是香料
We need herbs, so it's like aromatic herbs.
迷迭香  百里香  挨门塔尔
Rosemary, thyme and emmental.
还有一点
And a little...?
大麻
Weed.
等等
Hold on !
做沙拉用的
I make salads!
- 他们从这拿武器走了吗  - 不  我送去给他们的
- The ritals are gone with the weapons? - I delivered them.
- 哪啊  - 世界的尽头
- where? - At the end of the world.
- 沃夫纳格的一个赛道  - 我们追的不是抢劫犯
- A circuit in Vauvenargues. - We hold them. It's not the robbers,
是个驾驶员
it's pilots.
那又怎样
So what ?
我认识司机
I know the drivers.
能让他把花放下吗
He can leave my grass of Provence?
- 这是大家的财产  - 这是我的
- She's up to everyone. - It's mine.
- 不  - 放下
- No. - Put it down.
- 你放错地方了  - 给我放下
- You're badly placed. - Put my basilisk.
转弯的时候快点
Take a closer look at the fi!
你太慢了
我不舒服
I feel bad,
西尔万
Sylvain.
打电话给你妹
Call your sister.
- 现在吗  - 对
- Now ? - Yes !
罗科
Rocco.
这他妈是谁
- 我们现在怎么办  - 闭嘴
喂
Hello?
那个啥  出租
That's the taxi guy.
- 你给我弄好了吗  - 没有  抱歉
- Are you giving me ? - No sorry.
她挂了
She hung up ?
- 是她的风格  - 打过去
- It's all her. - Recall it.
- 什么  - 再打过去
- What? - Recall it.
嗯
Yeah?
我是西尔万
It's Sylvain
市政警察
the municipal police.
我在一个赛道上  我必须给两个意大利人一点教训
I am on a circuit. I have to teach a lesson to two Italian girls.
好吧  你可以进入设置
OK. You go in set-up,
换成竞赛模式
put yourself in race mode.
不  你不能用竞赛模式
No, you're not going to race or set-up.
没事儿的
Everything is fine.
胎压调到1.3帕
Increases to 1.3 bars
把刹车分配调整为前轮占比65后轮占比35
and adjusts the braking distribution 65 at the front, 35 at the rear
然后踩下油门
and press the pedal.
好了
That's good.
好点了
It's better.
- 我们是个优秀的团队  - 并不是
- We make a nice team. - No.
我会再打给你的
I'll call you back.
可别太得意了
Do not feel obligated.
她真难勾搭
She is hard.
准备好了吗
Are you ready ?
走
Go!
开慢点
Stop Please !
不
No !
爽呆了
Its good !
耶
Yeah!
意大利人这么菜的嘛
It's fragile Italian,
这样的速度
but to roll like that,
可谁也嬴不了
you will not break them!
这里禁止飙车  你想要干什么
It's forbidden here. What do you want ?
之前被人耍了  我很不爽
The stroke of the tram, it pissed me off.
我想
I wanted
训练一下  但不知道你们在跑了
to train, without knowing that you were running.
这红车真漂亮
the red is pretty,
是不是菲亚特500的引擎
but she has the engine of a Fiat 500?
那是我老婆的
That's his wife's.
- 对啊  - 卷毛  你要换个力气更大的东西
- Ah yes. - Hair, you need something powerful.
罗科
Rocco.
你小子很狂
You are arrogant.
但是个好车手
But you are a good pilot.
我明天晚上要跑几圈
I'm having an evening tomorrow.
如果想赚钱就过来  我会给你介绍几个人
If you want to make money, come on. I will introduce you to people.
好的  如果我有空的话
Yes, if I go through there.
出租司机
Taxi drivers,
都是好赛车手
they are good race drivers.
客人都催的很紧的  他们总去购物
In relation to the clientele, they go shopping.
他不能来
He does not come.
好了
There you go.
为什么是他不能来  为什么
Why him, he's not coming? Why?
他要来
He is coming!
你一直在工作吗
You're beating all the time.
你不用工作吗
You never.
在这儿是这样
It happens to me. Here,
- 给你的花  - 给我干什么
- flowers. - What do I do?
放在花瓶里
Put them in a vase.
谢谢
Thank you.
这还挺好看的
Usually, it's nice.
我还准备了个惊喜但是
I had a surprise but...
看起来你不方便  抱歉打扰了
I feel that I do not like you. Sorry for inconvenience.
我可没这么说
I did not say that.
解释一下  我是个好车手  但你不是模特
Explain to me, I am a good pilot but you, you are not a model of series.
你肯定是未打磨的那种  我也没有工程单
You must be a prototype, I do not have the technical sheet...
还有一束光照在我的心
There are lights that come on,
但我不知道是什么
but I do not know what it is.
如果我什么都没看到  肯定是搞错了
If I see nothing, maybe there is more windshield washer...
我明白了  你说完了吗
I understood. You've finished ?
完了
Yes.
我去准备一下
I'm going to get ready.
策略成功了
This technique works
- 对吧  - 别太得意
- so ? - Not get excited !
海洋公园
小心
Warning.
来吧
There you go !
你确定吗  我不太喜欢惊喜
Are you sure of yourself ? I do not like surprises.
这个
This one,
你永远不会忘记
you will never forget it.
- 好了吗  - 好了
- It's okay ? - Well yeah.
你这是要干什么
What's your delusion?
你跟海豚游过泳吗
Have you ever swam with dolphins?
混蛋
Whore !
- 没事吧  - 这是什么
- It's okay ? - What's this ?
这是什么啊
What's this ?
警告  此处危险 禁止翻越
海豚不在这边  我们走吧
It's not here, the dolphins. We will go
在另外一边  那里
in the other basin, there.
我不去了
Not with me.
只是水而已
It's just water!
你是怕鱼吗
Are you afraid of a fish?
我不是在开玩笑  冷静
I'm not kidding, stay calm!
来啊
Here!
我调查过了
I did my investigation,
奥利维亚6号的庄园
and the villa of 6 rue des Oliviers
属于伯纳索利先生  我不知道
belongs to Mrs. Bonassoli. I dunno
- 她知不知道什么意思  - 继续
- if she knows it means... - Go on.
嗯  庄园被安东尼奥・迪・拜斯租下了
Yes. The villa was rented by Antonio di Biase,
或是托尼・道格
or Toni Dog,
优秀的意大利车手
great Italian driver of the 2000s.
只是他跟那帮不勒斯的黑帮
Except that he got closer to the mafia
走得很近
Neapolitan.
另一个
The other.
是罗科
It's Rocco
长脖子斯蒂芬・西格尔  不  他是在逃犯
Long neck, Steven Seagal? No ! Rather NLP,
知道了吗
you see ?
犯有暴力侵犯和抢劫罪
Known for aggravated violence and robbery.
这里
Here.
怎么了
Yes?
这是你画的吗  真好看
Are you the drawings? They are beautiful.
谢谢  因为有照片只要临摹就好了
Thank you. As I had the photos, I made a layer
这样更好看
so, it's prettier...
很好  梅纳德
Bravo Menard.
更
More...
我们要参加这个派对
Have to go to this party.
有人想去吗
Volunteers ?
有吗
So who?
好吧  你可以来  不过要在
Okay, you will come and you will wait
角落等着
in a corner.
米歇尔
Michel
- 我需要你  - 好吧
- I need you. - OK,
你不是他的搭档
not his teammate.
你不能这么说
You do not have the right.
我不能去  还要打篮球
I can not, I have basketball.
什么
Sorry ?
打篮球  区比赛
Basketball, with the parish.
你呢
And you ?
我还有很多画要画
I have lots of drawings going on
而且我的手指都受伤了
and I have my hand contours project.
我还要画
And I Sandrine
桑德琳
To draw,
还要吃  像他们说的
to eat, as they say.
得要不少时间
Will need several leaves.
额  拉比  你给我们找个
Uh... Larbi, you find us
- 耳机  - 好的
- auricles. - Yes.
散会
Go!
中招了吧
I had you well.
今日最佳笑话
The joke of the day!
你这混蛋
You look con.
我卡住了
We are stuck!
干的漂亮
Good.
好黏啊
It really sticks!
梅纳德  你这个混蛋
Menard, you're pissing!
听得到吗
You hear me ?
我是矮子  不是个聋子
I'm dwarf, not deaf.
- 我说的是耳机  - 到
- In the atrium. - Yes.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
- 要饮料不  - 不 谢谢
- A sofa ? - No thanks.
一杯都不要吗
Not even leather?
- 你怎么过来了  - 我警告过你
- You're here ? - I warned you.
那是什么
What is that ?
我现在是服务生
I'm in Donnie Brasco.
我们必须渗透进去  喂
We must infiltrate. Hello?
喂
Oh!
- 喂  老大  - 对  我们要渗透进去
- Oh, champion! - Yes, have to infiltrate.
你还在听我说吗  执行任务的时候
Are you with me? Guy George, stay focused
- 专心点儿  - 好  不好意思
- on the mission. - Yes excuse me.
任务是
The mission :
- 我们去找线索  - 你说得对
- we come back and get some clues. - You're right.
- 好吧  - 我们分两队  你  我  还有
- Here. - We make 2 teams of 2: you, me and...
他去哪了
Where is he ?
- 好吧  我们分两队  - 不是
- Well, we'll do 2 teams of 1. - No.
还两队  不就是单干吗
2 teams? 2 teams all alone, what.
你害怕了吗
'You are scared ?
我不怕  但他们看上去很厉害
I'm not scared, but the ritals look sturdy.
你叔叔难道也是这样吗
Your uncle would have reacted like that?
啊  对啊  扎铁了吧
Ah, yes, there, it stings where it hurts, huh?
- 没错  - 听我说
- That is true. - Listen.
要是我找不回来线索  我妈就没小鸡鸡
My mother, chuckle her if I do not bring any clues.
- 我喜欢这劲头  - 我也是
- I like this energy. - Me too.
好啊
That's good.
走
Go!
- 能听到我说话吗  - 我到位了
- Do you receive me? - I'm at my post.
我叫米歇尔
My name is Michel.
辛西娅
Cynthia.
- 很高兴认识你  辛西娅  - 我也是
- Nice to meet you, Cynthia. - Enchanted.
你知道塔赫纳吗  可美了
Do you know Cartagena? That's wonderful.
像你一样
Like you.
我的天啊
你在这儿啊  快点  我们走
You're here ? Come on, let's go.
- 你走开  - 怎么
- Leave me. - How?
别管我
Leave me.
额  对不起
Uh, sorry,
- 但我们不是来找乐子的  - 我说了
- but we are not here to have fun. - I told you
离我远点儿
to leave me!
我们可以好好聊天的  我铁被扎了
We can talk to each other normally. I'm not fine !
不好意思  刚说到哪儿了
Excuse me. Where was I? Portable
- 沙滩  宝贝儿  - 喂  你在哪儿
- The beach, children... - Hello? Where are you ?
我在办公室找到了些图片
有人来了  我先挂了
你是藏在垃圾桶里
You hid in the trash
混进来的吗
to enter ?
我  不是  我在做任务
Me ? No, I'm doing something,
- 但是这是秘密  - 你还是不会撒谎
- but it's secret. - Still your shisha without lactose,
- 就这样吗  - 是啊  这可不是无麸食品推销
- that's it ? - Already, it's gluten-free chichas.
而是有野心的男人的事业
And it's an ambitious guy thing,
小姐
Mrs.
等等
Hold on.
别告诉别人  好吗
You do not repeat, OK?
我在卧底
I'm undercover.
我为警察工作
I work for the police.
好厉害的
A sick thing.
我认识个人
I met a guy,
- 我们就搭档了  - 真是
- we do a team. - The funniest,
搞笑  我还以为你变了
for a moment, I thought you had changed.
怎么回事儿
What's this ?
- 现在怎么办  - 那是我女票
- What now ? - There's my girl.
她跟别的男人在一起  而且  他们很帅
She's with guys. In addition, they are beautiful.
什么图片  快点
你看看
就是这个
他们可能就是要偷这个
- 应该就是这个  - 对  应该就是
这就是他们的目标
对  这就是他们的目标
有人来了好像
嘘
Hush.
我不认识你
你也不认识我
不行
I can not.
- 抬屁股  - 太高了
- The ass. - Too high.
让开  你太胖了
Move, you're too fat.
那儿会被发现的
要不呢
Or ?
动动脑子啊
小心点
晚上好
Good evening.
进度怎么样了
Where are we now?
都到位了
It is in place.
准备好了
It's ready.
你一直
You have been
很有效率
very effective.
这可是全世界
There, it is the biggest
最大的钻石
diamond of the world.
不能犯任何错误
No right to the error.
你可以相信我们
You can trust us.
到达时间呢
Arriving time ?
上午11点  直升机过来
For 11am, by helicopter,
当天从日内瓦来
from Geneva, the same day.
我们会处理警察那边
We take care of the police.
完美
It's perfect.
怎么付款呢
And the payment?
别担心  交货后24小时之内就会办妥的
Do not worry, it will be done within 24 hours after the operation.
嗯  好  很高兴
Ah! Here ! It's a pleasure to work
跟你合作  合作愉快
with you. That's when you want.
好
Yeah.
这俩傻逼
- 怎么处理他们  - 干掉
很好
哎呀  哎呀
Yes Yes...
噢
Ouch.
- 起来  - 你好  没事吧
- Get up. - Hello. It's okay ?
- 你在这干什么  - 我在跟我朋友
- What are you doing here ? - I'm doing a hide and seek
玩躲猫猫  西尔万
with my friend... Sylvain!
我们迷路了
We lost !
你们找到了我们  恭喜  这儿呢
You found us, congratulations! Oh there ! Well...
混蛋
Whore.
卡洛
Carlo.
下来吧
Come down.
我们迷路了  能不能好好说
We lost, there. Maybe they are nice?
我自己来  自己来
It's good, it's good.
好了
It's okay!
再见  司机
Ciao, pilot.
你要介绍人给我  我来了
Did you want to introduce people to me? I'm here.
天啊
Oh dear !
天啊撸
Oh me too.
罗科  你让他给我开口
Rocco, you make him talk.
这个杀掉吧
He, you kill him.
什么意思
What do you mean ?
杀掉吗
You kill him?
我们可以换一下吗
We can reverse.
长官
Sir?
和我在一起时
When you're with me
你是什么感觉
What do you feel?
你能告诉我吗
Will you tell me
即使我不告诉你
Even I won 't tell you
祝你玩得开心
看得出来那是
I can tell that it was love
一见钟情
At first sight
如果我爱你
If l love you
那么
So ?
你就别装了  你们在找什么
You do not behave anymore. What are you looking for ?
我什么都不会说的
I will not say anything.
我不是警官  知道吗
I'm not a police officer, yes.
是他在找线索  因为他知道你们要偷
He was looking for clues because he knows you're going to steal...
闭嘴
Shut up.
我在跟他说话呢  他找到了
I speak with the gentleman. He found
钻石的线索
the clues on the diamond.
- 闭嘴  - 停  他好像有点疼
- Shut up. .. - Stopped. He is painful.
- 太好了  - 没问题  应该的
- Bravo. - No problem, it's normal.
- 做得好  - 谢谢
- Good game. - Thank you.
我能走了吗
I can go ?
你觉得可能吗
不让走吗
就这样吗
That's it ?
每天都是你
To you everyday
米歇尔  如果你能听到
Michel, if you hear me
我们在一楼  走廊旁边第三扇门
we are on the 1st, 3rd door of the corridor,
有个蠢货想杀我们  快来
a moron wants to kill us.
好
Good.
不
OH NO !
我去去就来
I'll be back.
我会
For you,
好好招待你的
I have what it takes.
谢谢
Thank you.
好啊
It's nice.
至于你
And for you,
既然你这么聪明  我准备了个小礼物
since you are clever, I have a small gift.
- 他还不错啊  - 听着
- he is nice. - Listen,
我们跳窗出去
we'll jump out the window.
我们会摔死自己的
We're going to fuck our breeds.
你是真的傻还是故意装的
Are you completely stupid or are you doing it on purpose?
不
No !
好吧你是真傻  如果呆在这  我们就死定了
You're completely stupid. If we stay there, we're dead.
数到三我们就跳窗  你跳不跳
At 3, we jump out the window. Are you with me?
- 准备好没有  - 好了
- Are you ready? - Yes !
数到三
At three.
深呼吸
Breathe.
来吧  1  2
Come on, one, two...
Three!
不
Oh no!
我的没有碎啊
Mine does not break.
- 我下不去了  - 做个蠢货还是挺好的
- I can not come. - It's fascinating to be so stupid.
- 从我那个窗户下来  - 你不明白
- Go through mine! - You did not understand.
我要是明白
If I understood.
- 但是  艾迪  - 弄不碎啊
- But... Eddy! - She does not break.
从我那个窗户下来
Go through mine.
快
Come !
他来了
He is coming !
你来啦  他走了
There you go. He left there.
- 妈的  - 窗户破了
- Shit ! - It broke it.
之前你说
In any case,
会好好招待  是有大鱼大肉吗
it's a nice reception. The meat is halal?
你死定了
我知道
I understand,
都是他干的  又不是我想的
he degraded material... I did not want to...
没必要这样  啊
It's not worth it. Ah!
哎呀呀
AIE Aie Aie !
这次又是谁
Who's that yet?
怎么样
So ?
该谢谢谁啊
Thanks WHO ?
谢谢你  米歇尔
Thank you, Michel.
走
Here.
市政警察
这是仙后座钻石
Here is the Cassiopeia,
意大利人的新目标
the new target of our Italians.
我们必须做好一切准备
We must be ready for anything.
保护和惩罚
好大啊
It's too big.
我们不行的
We will not be up to it.
你需要真的警察
You need real cops.
他们中有内奸
There are ripoux at home.
- 我们不能跟那些混蛋透漏任何消息  - 听着
- We say nothing to these bastards. - Listen,
我到这儿的时候  还不知道有什么在等着我
when I arrived, I did not know what was waiting for me.
我觉得你们都讨厌我
I felt that you hated me,
我也讨厌你们
so I hated you.
如果我都能改变
If I changed
你们也可以
and you too,
每个人
is that everyone
都可以
can happen
改变
to change !
这不是洛基4的台词吗
It's not in Rocky 4 ?
你给我闭嘴
Yes, shut up.
哦
Oh!
雷吉斯
Regis!
- 不不  - 别盯着他看
- No no ! - Do not look at him.
把武器收起来
Put the weapon back...
就像那样
Like that.
都是因为他太高兴了
It's because he's happy.
冷静点
Calms you.
好的  我们出发吧
Here. Well, here we go.
准备好了吗
Ready?
准备好了
HE CHEF!
松鼠正在接近
Squirrel approaching.
保护这片区域  所有人各司其职
Secure the area, each one his post.
好的
OK.
坏警察到了
The ripoux are there.
- 这样不好  我们是同事  所以  - 是的
- Warning. We are colleagues, so... - Yes.
- 不能这样  - 不吗
- Can not. - No.
这太不专业了
It's not professional.
你的朋友们  靠谱吗
Your friends, is it good?
一般般吧
Normally.
你开始发热了
You're feverish.
我才没有
I'm not feverish.
- 我没有发热  - 梅纳德
- I am not feverish. - Menard,
能听到我吗
you receive me ?
收到了  TC  结束
Affirmative, Tango, Charlie, finished.
- 我爱你  - 这很正常
- I love you. - It's normal.
米歇尔
Michel?
- 米歇尔  - 我到位了
- Michel? - I'm in place.
长官  你好
Mr. Prefect, hello.
是我组织的这次行动
It was I who organized the operation.
我动用了最好的队伍
I mobilized the finest teams.
珠宝用直升机从日内瓦被运过来  会降落在那儿
The jewel arrives from Geneva by helicopter. He will land there.
那个圆圈里
There is a round.
一切都被被布置的像音乐会一样周密
Everything is set like in a music basket, quiet.
松鼠即将抵达
Squirrel with Mucem.
它在那儿
Here it is.
- 看到直升机了  - 我觉得  我会和她滚床单的
- Helicopter in sight. - I'm going to fuck her, I think.
没想到啊
Unexpected.
那是什么
What is that ?
无人机的正确拼法是Drone
那看起来像一个污人机  是个污无人机
It looks like a "brone". It's a "brone".
污人机吗
A brone?
我说的就是这个啊  污人机
That's what I say, a brone.
问题是
Problem is.
这他喵是哪儿来的
where does he come from?
别走啊
Stay here.
你打扰到我了
You disturb.
- 什么  - 早上好  市长先生
-  What? - Good morning, Mr. Mayor.
你有一分钟的时间
You have a minute
来命令你的驾驶员跟着我们的无人机飞走
to order the pilot to follow our drone.
什么
Ah! What?
我会
I'm messing
当众出丑的
in front of the joke.
如果你觉得
If you believe
可以威胁我  那你就
impress me, you put your finger
大错特错了
in the knee.
他是傻逼吗
应该是吧
好吧
OK.
那就来点儿刺激的吧
It's going to be crazy.
真是胡闹
The mytho.
这不是胡闹
It's not mytho.
今天早在弗雷尤斯的珠宝就被偷走了
It was stolen this morning at Frejus.
让他们看看我们是不是在开玩笑
卡洛
你知道该怎么做
You know it
- 各个分队  - 放松
- To all units... - Relax.
天啊
oh my god.
那是怎么回事
What's this ?
太好了
Bravo.
联系上飞行员了吗
飞行员先生
Mr. Pilot,
请跟着你旁边的无人机飞走
follow the drone where you are
好的
OK.
不  发生什么了
No ! What's happening ?
直升机飞走了  我们该做什么
The helicopter goes off. What do we do ?
我们上吧
We improvise.
不
No.
我不同意
Disagree.
- 他要开去哪儿  - 阻止它
- He where goes this one? - Stop it!
米歇尔  该你了
Michel, yours.
好的
OK.
走你
Let's go.
牛逼
Shit.
喂  小巴
Hello Baba?
计划有变
Change:
清空大街
clear the road.
我们在追
We follow
一架直升飞机
a helicopter.
好的  我来处理
OK, I manage.
好的  多谢
OK, thanks.
伙计们  你们去堵住主路出口
Guys, you're blocking boulevard access,
给出租车腾出畅通无阻的路
the taxi must have free field.
停下  就等两分钟
Stop, 2 minutes.
搞定了
Its good.
- 喂  - 发生什么了
- Yeah? - What is happening?
直升机后面有个出租车跟屁虫
The helicopter has the taxi to the buttocks.
出租车吗  我来解决
The taxi ? I'm taking care of it.
他们死定了
卡林  他们吵得我耳朵疼
Karim, they hurt my head.
不怪我  是他要这样的
It's not me, it's him.
- 它开的好快啊  - 你们在这儿啊
- It goes quickly. - There you are !
我们走
Let's go.
放开我
Let go of me.
你这个侏儒是从哪儿冒出来的
Where does this dwarf come from?
你在干什么
What are you doing ?
你会飞到天上去的
You'll go up in the air,
草泥马的
fuck your mother!
他们更快一点
They are faster.
走着瞧
We'll see.
他们在那儿
They are there.
别担心  没事的
Do not worry, it's okay.
但他在干什么
But what does he do?
停下
Stopped !
让他妈这些法国人见佛祖去吧
In fact, please send it to Fmm?fisa
那个傻逼侏儒呢  看着点
Where is this dwarf con? Watch!
- 吃我一雨刷  - 把他弄下去了
- Take this. - Get him out of there.
看啊  他被甩出去了
Here! He's broken the playmobil!
上高速你可不就是我的对手了
- 他们非常厉害  - 我知道
- They are powerful. - I know.
加速了
Accelerated.
再快点
闭嘴  让我专心点
你是吃干饭的吗
给我闭嘴
时速多少了
How much are you?
别看  没事的
Do not look. It's okay.
我们可能会死
We can die.
我知道
I know
你们要上这边
that you are here!
超过他
干他
你不是警察
You're not a cop,
警察不会这么开车的
a cop does not roll like that.
快点
Come on !
那有一辆卡车
There's a truck there.
西尔万  我们别过去
Sylvain, we do not go.
走你
It goes.
我们差点被一辆卡车压死
We almost got run over by a truck!
这不没事儿吗
This happened.
梅纳德
Menard,
- 你们阻止他们了吗  - 我们即兴发挥了  但准备好了
- did you stop them? - We improvise, but it's ready.
十秒钟后袭击
Impact in 1Os.
这是什么
What's this ?
好大啊
It's big.
现在
Now.
我爱你
I love you !
- 这是什么  - 这是什么
- What is it ? - What's this ?
就像头猪一样
It's like a boar.
别碰她
Do not touch it.
- 她是我的女朋友  - 你想要什么
- She is my girlfriend. - What do you want?
我会保护她的  别碰她
I'll protect her. Do not touch her pistol.
闭嘴  把她带走
Shut up and clear.
- 我被撞惨了  - 妈的
- I got screwed. - fucking shit.
快点儿啊
我的胃不舒服
I have the sheaf.
憋不住了  要放屁了
My gas is coming back.
给我憋好了
Stop with that.
这又不是我的错
It's not my fault.
他们要开枪了
They will shoot.
他们开枪了
They shoot !
- 我看到了  - 用的可是真子弹
- I saw ! - With real bullets.
妈的
Shit !
打给雷吉斯
Call me Regis.
什么  你想干什么  雷吉斯
What? If you want. Regis!
不是叫我雷吉斯  是打给雷吉斯
Not me ! Call Regis,
- 那个警察  - 那个虐待狂吗
- the policeman. - The sadist?
- 没错  - 好吧
- Here! - OK.
雷吉斯
Regis?
在  我跟着你呢
Yes, I follow you.
那直升机呢
And the helicopter?
他被导航去了
He directs himself
三公里外的一个游艇上
to a yacht at 3km.
- 他们和我们中间隔着海呢  - 我们走
- They are blocked by the sea. - Let's go.
谢谢你  雷吉斯
Thank you, Regis.
不
No.
他们要开枪了
They will shoot.
救命
Help.
- 能听到吗  - 能
- You hear me ? - Yes.
他们要打下直升机  他们要打下来
They will go down the propeller. They will take it down!
手提箱丢下去
The suitcase.
打电话给你妹妹
Call your sister.
怎么了
Yeah?
我跟你哥哥在一起
I'm with your brother,
- 我们有麻烦了  - 说吧
- We are in trouble. - Yes.
有辆兰博基尼在粘着我
I have an Aventador who sticks to me.
我必须赶快
I must smoke it
- 甩掉他  - 右边的驻车制动旁边
- in 3 s. - To the right of the parking brake,
有个一次性的加速装置
you have a turbo boost single use.
别这样  相信我
You do not do what I believe.
- 不  - 坐稳了
- No. - Hang in there.
one,
two,
three!
不  不  不
Oh no ! No no !
走
Go.
对不起打扰你们的雅兴了
We are sorry for the inconvenience.
我们就是来取个东西
We just have things to recover.
不  不
No! No!
不
No !
不  不
No ! No
- 她死掉了  - 别在这儿吵吵
- She is dead ! - Not here.
- 她死了  死了  - 去把他们绑起来
- She is dead ! Dead! - Go tie them up.
不是他们
Not them,
- 艾迪  - 怎么了
- Eddy! - What ?
是他们啊
They, there.
啊  走  走
Ah! Go! Go!
把手给我
Laaefia
这不重要
It's not important.
她死了啊
She is dead !
没死呢
Not dead,
就是车头撞了  没事的
in front of her a little morfle, it's not...
找个好铂金工就行了  会没事的
A good bodybuilder, it knows how to work. It will be fine.
啊  烦死我了
Ah! It's annoying me !
- 什么事  - 市长先生
- What is ? - Mr. Mayor?
- 马丁  怎么样了  - 我们找到钻石了  找到了
- Martin, what's going on? - We found the diamond. We did it.
很好  我在听音乐呢
Good, I listen to music.
- 你能听到我吗  - 可以啊
- Can you hear me ? - I hear more.
艾迪
Eddy.
- 艾迪  - 什么
- Edd - Yes?
过来了
I arrive.
任务结束
End of mission.
只有抓到案件主谋才能算结束
It will be over when we have caught the ritals.
别担心  他们就在那儿
Do not worry, they're just there,
等着我们呢
they are waiting for us.
别动
- 你在想什么  - 冷静
混蛋们  这一下是为了06年的事情  这是复仇
The ritals, that one is for Zizou in 2006, it is revenge.
嘿  你会游泳吗
Hey, can you swim?
泳池里会  下海就不会了
In the pool, not in the sea
- 什么在碰我  - 有鱼
- What's touching me? - Fin!
鲨鱼
Aileron!
不要
No !
赶走她
Stop her !
手放在方向盘上
Hands on the steering wheel.
一分钟
One minute.
你是个好车手
You're a good pilot.
我是马洛特中尉  根据交通法规
Lieutenant Marot. Strong rights granted to me
第71  72和74条之规定
and according to articles 71, 72 and 74
你超速并危险驾驶
on crime and speeding,
我将亲自处理你的车辆
I personally seize the vehicle.
是台好车
It's nice.
我们会再见的
We'll meet Again.
最近很少听到
We hear it less
你们这么狂的人了  真是怀念啊
your big mouth. You bring her back less.
臭娘们
好吧
Okay...
- 你吃什么了吗  - 对  我吃水了
- You got something. - Yes, I was there.
- 满嘴都是水  - 我要怎么跟哈米德叔叔说
- In full mouth. - And what do I say to uncle Hamid?
我还得告诉我妹妹
And I must warn my sister.
她就交给我吧
She, I take care of it.
是我把车弄坏的  也该我去说
It's me who broke the car, it's up to me to assume.
我会处理的  剩下的交给你了
I'm taking care of it. Secures the perimeter.
好吧  我终于安全了
OK. Well then I secure, me, okay.
所以
So,
好消息是我没事
good news, I'm fine,
坏消息是出租车
bad news, the taxi...
对  电视上都在放
Yes, it's on TV.
关于这次逮捕你能告诉我们什么
What can you tell us about this arrest?
唐尼.布拉索出自电影《忠奸人》
我履行了自己作为警察的职责  像唐尼.布拉索一样
I did my duty as a policeman, like Donnie Brasco
或者说杰森・伯恩
or Jason Bourne.
杰森・伯恩出自电影《谍影重重》
但是我这次不是孤军奋战
But I was not alone I take advantage
因为多亏了我的朋友西尔万
to make a dedication to my friend Sylvain.
我们是支好团队
We're doing a great team.
- 希望能再合作  - 请你放开麦克风
- I hope we will do it again. - Leave the microphone.
我们比绝地战警还厉害
We are better than Bad Boy.
我是劳伦斯先生
I am Mr Lawrence...
- 放手  - 你是威尔史密斯
- Proud. - You're Will Smith.
谢谢
Thank you
- 你的自信  - 说得真好
- for your confidence. - Beautiful binomial
- 我们终于有机会了  - 还有萨米亚
- we have the opportunity... - And Samia,
- 我是你哥哥  - 妈的
- He is your brother.- Whore !
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我来这儿也要感谢你  谢谢你  妹妹
I'm here thanks to you too, thank you sister.
我生命中的女人
And the woman of my life,
她叫桑迪
Sandy's name
- 你让我开始生气了  - 桑迪  我爱你
- You start to piss me off. - Sandy, I love you.
你的宝贝泰迪小熊熊会永远让你如痴如梦
Your plump teddy bear will always be there to make you dream.
嫁给我吧
Marry me !
- 放开麦克风  - 好吗
- Leave the microphone. - Hein?
我爱你
I love you !
- 谢谢  - 你就是我这辈子的女人
- Thank you. - You are the woman of my life.
- 我的小宝贝  - 西尔万  做我的见证人
- Plump little bear cub. - Sylvain, be my witness.
好了  谢谢  谢谢
Well, thank you, thank you...
出租车  他死没了  出租车开不了了
The taxi, he's dead. There, the taxi is over.
我不喜欢那样  见了鬼了
I do not like working like this. Shit !
伊斯万
Islam,
在孚日山脉的报道
in the Vosges.
采访对象
This subject that...
现在必须走了
Must leave now.
谁能让他从镜头前面走开
Can someone clear him from the field of view?
对不起弄坏了车
Sorry for the taxi.
他已经风光过了  这个结局很好
He has had his day. He had a beautiful ending.
我也有个惊喜
I have a surprise.
能回去高兴吗
Glad to return
回北方去
in the far north?
也许我会留下呢  不过没什么值得我留念的
I would have stayed, but there is nothing that holds me back...
好比说一个我很喜欢的女孩
Like a super girl that I like a lot,
跟我有一样的热情
who shares the same passion.
一个教我最美的事就是最值得做的事的女孩
A girl who would have taught me that the most beautiful things are worthy.
哦  不是吧
Oh dear !
真的  都还没亲上呢
This, really, it's not done!
你以为这样就能勾搭上我吗
You thought you had me like that?
- 这样不好  - 对不起
- It's not good. - Sorry,
但是你的声音都变的柔软了
but you've changed your voice altogether.
- 我这么投入  这么真诚呢  - 我看到了
- I am thoroughly in, sincere. - I saw !
- 你一点都不浪漫吗  - 当然不是了
- Are not you romantic? - Of course yes !
这太简单了
It's too easy.
- 简单  - 对
- Too easy ? - Yes !
跟你亲一个都这么难
Given the galley it is to kiss,
我都不敢想像该怎么跟你一起睡
I do not even imagine sleeping with you.
确实是
It is deserved.
- 你想亲我啊  - 是
- You want to kiss me ? - Yes.
那就下去
Then down.
不太好吧
I'm not fine,
20米呢
20m!
只是水而已啊
It's just water.
- 跳就跳  - 去吧
- When to go. - Come on.
会不会跳到石头上
Maybe we could jump to stone?
不会  跳就是了
No, go ahead first.
- 安全吗  - 当然
- Safe ? - Yes.
鱼咬你屁股了
The dish on the ass!
很爽的  我们都会浮起来
I had fun! All the weight on the same!
- 来吧  - 水太凉了
- Come. - Finally, she's cold.
- 什么  - 我也不想下去
- What? - I do not feel it too much.
别啊  来吧
No, but come!
音乐停
The music !
市长先生
Mr. Mayor.
绶带  抱歉  抱歉
The scarf, sorry. Sorry.
市民们  市民们
Citizens, citizens,
我为我们的警员们骄傲
I am proud of our municipal police
他们揭发了警察里面的内奸
the Mumu, who has just unveiled rogue police!
比松  拿奖章来
Bichon, the medals!
亲爱的
Oh dear!
- 音乐起  - 恭喜
- Music! - Congratulations.
干得好
Bravo.
市长授予你的
From the mayor.
谢谢
Thank you.
代表城市感谢你
The city thanks you.
- 代表马赛感谢你  - 谢谢
- Marseille thanks you. - Thank you.
哦
Oh!
我们都很感激你
We thank you.
我爱你
I love you !
我他妈是真爱你啊
I love you fucking.
我为你感到骄傲  你跟你那口子还好吧
I'm proud of you. It's okay with your darling.
很好  看看我给她准备的东西
Great. Look what I'm going to offer him.
- 这是你偷的吗  - 不是
- Did you steal it? - No.
- 从意大利佬那儿偷的  - 没有
- Yes, to the Italians. - No.
我只偷了个被盗的戒指而已
And even! I stole a stolen ring,
没人会发现
it vanishes.
我们要不要
So, we do
一起去兜一圈
his request?
你要去哪儿啊
Where are you going ?
我要在25分钟内赶到机场
I have to be at the airport in 25 minutes.
25分钟绰绰有余啊
25 minutes, it's wide.
不  25分钟
No, 25 minutes,
根本不可能
it's impossible.
我还要去市政厅
I have a snack
吃自助呢  好多好吃的呢
with the municipal... There are four quarters,
你要一起来吗
you come?